Final level 1 has a format string vulnerability that can be exploited remotely.
最终级别1存在可远程利用的格式字符串漏洞。
Over the past few videos we have learned how to talk to these programs over a TCP network
在过去的几段视频中，我们学习了如何通过TCP网络与这些程序通信。
connection and how to debug them, so we are all set to go.
连接以及如何调试它们，所以我们都准备好了。
Like all previous challenges, the program is running as a network daemon in this case
与所有以前的挑战一样，在本例中，该程序作为网络守护程序运行
on port 2994.
在2994号港口。
So we can use netcat to connect to this service which displays a final1 prompt.
所以我们可以使用netcat连接到显示final1提示的服务。
But when we enter something we don’t see anything.
但当我们进入某个地方，却什么也看不见。
Mh.
马来酸酐
Also because we already know it will be about a format string vulnerability, we can try
另外，因为我们已经知道这将是一个格式字符串漏洞，我们可以尝试
to inject some characters such as %x, but again, nothing happens.
注入一些字符，如%x，但同样，什么也不会发生。
We could also try %s, because if you remember, it will take values on the stack as the address
我们也可以尝试使用%s，因为如果您记得，它将以堆栈上的值作为地址
location of a string, thus if values on the stack do not point into valid memory, the
字符串的位置，因此，如果堆栈上的值未指向有效内存，则
program should crash, which would be another indication of a format string vulnerability.
程序应该崩溃，这将是格式字符串漏洞的另一个指示。
But nope.
但是没有。
Also doesn’t do anything.
也不做任何事。
We could also try to send a very long string, just to see if there is a buffer overflow
我们还可以尝试发送一个非常长的字符串，只是为了查看是否存在缓冲区溢出。
that would crash the program, but also doesn’t work.
这会使程序崩溃，但也不起作用。
You can see that the prompt got returned now multiple times, which is an indication that
您可以看到现在多次返回提示，这表示
the program always reads a limited amount of characters, and you sent so many at once,
程序总是读取有限数量的字符，而您一次发送了如此多的字符，
that the read loop was able to read many times.
读取循环能够读取多次。
So I guess it’s time to have a look at the source code.
所以我想是时候看看源代码了。
Main calls two functions after setting up all the networking stuff.
在设置完所有的网络设备后，MAIN调用两个函数。
The first one is getipport(), and the second one is parser().
第一个是getipport() ，第二个是parser() 。
Getipport calls the function getpeername(), so let’s see what that is about.
getipport调用getpeername() 函数，让我们看看这是怎么回事。
getpeername() returns the address of the peer connected to the socket sockfd, in the buffer
getpeername() 返回缓冲区中连接到socket sockfd的对等机的地址
pointed to by addr.
由地址指向。
We can see that it also defines a struct sockaddr_in which apparently will then contain the source
我们可以看到，它还定义了一个结构sockaddr_，其中显然将包含源代码
ip address and source port by the client that connected to the socket.
连接到套接字的客户端的IP地址和源端口。
You can also look up how the struct exactly looks like on the man page for ip.
您还可以在IP的手册页上查找结构的确切外观。
So it will basically contain the port number, and the ip address, and the ip address is
所以它基本上包含端口号和IP地址，IP地址是
a 32byte integer.
32字节的整数。
And sprintf will write this constructed string into hostname, which is a global variable.
sprintf将把这个构造好的字符串写到hostname中，hostname是一个全局变量。
Ok so once this function is complete, the code will call parser().
好的，所以一旦函数完成，代码将调用parser() 。
And parser will print the final1 prompt we already know.
解析器将打印我们已经知道的最后一个提示。
Then it uses fgets to read 128 bytes into the line buffer.
然后它使用fgets将128个字节读取到行缓冲区中。
After that it uses trim, which looks for the first occurrence of a newline or linefeed
然后它使用trim，它查找换行符或换行符的第一个匹配项
and replaces it with a 0.
并将其替换为0。
Basically cutting the string at these positions.
基本上就是在这些位置切割绳子。
Then it will check if the string you entered starts with “username”, or “login”.
然后它将检查您输入的字符串是否以“用户名”或“登录”开头。
Ahh, ok, so there are special commands for that prompt.
啊，好的，所以这个提示有一些特殊的命令。
If you enter username, it kinda expects additional data after it, because it string copies anything
如果您输入用户名，它在后面会有一些额外的数据，因为它字符串会复制任何内容。
after the “username” part into the global variable username.
在“username”部分之后进入全局变量username。
If you would use the command “login”, it would check if you specified a username
如果您要使用命令“login”，它将检查您是否指定了用户名
before, if not it tells you you follow a wrong protocol.
之前，如果没有，它会告诉你遵循了一个错误的协议。
But if you specified a username before, it will call logit, with a pointer into the string
但是如果您之前指定了一个用户名，它将调用logit，并在字符串中插入一个指针。
after login, because it expects a password there.
在登录之后，因为它需要一个密码。
The password is not used in logit, it’s just a mockup for the challenge, but in there
密码不在logit中使用，它只是挑战的一个模型，但在那里
it uses a buffer and writes to it with snprintf.
它使用一个缓冲区并用snprintf写入。
Basically creating a line for a log entry, that says that there was a login attempt from
基本上是为一个日志条目创建一行，这表示有一个登录尝试来自
a certain client for a specific user with a certain password.
具有特定密码的特定用户的特定客户端。
And then this string logged in the system log.
然后这个字符串记录在系统日志中。
Then this function returns and it will print “login failed”.
然后此函数返回，并将打印“登录失败”。
Armed with this knowledge we can try to use the prompt again.
有了这些知识，我们可以再次尝试使用提示。
And it does what we expect.
它做了我们所期望的。
Now this failed login attempt should have been logged in the syslog.
现在，这个失败的登录尝试应该记录在系统日志中。
So let’s check it out.
我们来看看。
Note you have to be root to read that file.
注意，您必须是根目录才能读取该文件。
So tail, to only get the last few lines, of /var/log/syslog
所以tail，只获取/var/log/syslog的最后几行
And there it is, final1 Login attempt from this source IP and source port, as LiveOverflow
在这里，从这个源IP和源端口的final1登录尝试，作为liveoverflow
with the password.
使用密码。
Okay.
可以。
But where the heck is the format string vulnerability?
但是格式字符串漏洞到底在哪里呢？
There is no printf where we controlled the format parameter.
我们控制格式参数的地方没有printf。
Why am I so hasty?
为什么我这么匆忙？
We don’t even fully understand the code yet, do we?
我们还没有完全理解代码，是吗？
We read this code with certain assumptions without questioning if they are true.
我们在阅读这段代码时，会有一些假设，如果它们是真的，我们会毫不怀疑。
The meaning of hacking, if anything, is about understanding computers on a deeper level.
黑客的意义，如果有的话，是关于更深层次的理解计算机。
But there is one function where we got lazy and brushed over, because we assumed it does
但有一个功能让我们变得懒惰和被忽视，因为我们认为它确实如此
it’s job.
这是工作。
If you take anything away from the stuff I create, then it shall be, don’t be satisfied
如果你从我创造的东西中拿走了任何东西，那就是，不要满足
with what you think you know, challenge your beliefs.
用你认为你知道的去挑战你的信仰。
Ok, well that rant was a bit overplaying it.
好吧，那咆哮有点夸张了。
But we did not look into this new function we encountered - syslog.
但是我们没有研究我们遇到的这个新函数-syslog。
I guess what I’m saying is, when you solve these simple challenges, you reach a point
我想我要说的是，当你解决这些简单的挑战时，你达到了一个点
where you think you know every dangerous function, but that’s not true.
你认为你知道所有危险的功能，但那不是真的。
So don’t get lazy, and read the man page.
所以别偷懒了，读一下手册。
If we look at the man page of syslog we will see that the second parameter is a format
如果我们查看syslog的手册页，我们将看到第二个参数是一种格式
parameter.
参数。
syslog() generates a log message, which will be distributed by syslogd(8).
syslog() 生成一条日志消息，由syslogd（8）分发。
The priority argument is formed by ORing the facility and the level values (explained below).
优先级参数是通过ORing设备和级别值形成的（如下所述）。
The remaining arguments are a format, as in printf(3)
其余参数是一种格式，如printf（3）中所示。
Syslog works like printf.
Syslog的工作方式与printf类似。
And buf in logit(), is the format parameter.
在logit() 中，buf是格式参数。
And buf will simply contain the username and password we entered, and thus we can inject
buf只包含我们输入的用户名和密码，因此我们可以注入
format characters.
设置字符格式。
Let’s try it.
让我们试试看。
Let’s login with %x stuff.
让我们用%x东西登录。
Login failed, check the syslog.
登录失败，请检查系统日志。
And there it is.
就在那里。
In brackets you can see the leaked values from the stack.
在括号中，您可以看到堆栈中泄漏的值。
Perfect, now we have identified the bug.
很好，现在我们已经识别出了这个错误。
And from earlier format string exploit videos we learned that a good strategy is to overwrite
从早期的格式字符串利用视频，我们了解到一个好的策略是覆盖
an address in the global offset table with another function, like system to execute commands.
全局偏移量表中的一个地址，具有另一个函数，如执行命令的系统。
Let’s think about what function would be convenient to overwrite.
让我们考虑一下覆盖什么函数比较方便。
I think, the strncmp is a cool function, because we control the first parameter.
我认为strncmp是一个很酷的函数，因为我们控制第一个参数。
The line.
这条线。
And system uses the first parameter for the string to execute stuff.
系统使用字符串的第一个参数来执行任务。
So if we replace strncmp with system, we can simply type in a line and execute a shell
因此，如果我们用系统替换strncmp，我们可以简单地键入一行并执行shell
command.
命令。
Ok, so let’s construct our exploit.
好吧，让我们来构建我们的开发。
We import what might be important, and setup the remote socket connection like we are used
我们导入可能重要的内容，并像使用一样设置远程套接字连接
to.
去。
And maybe we create a new function called, read_until.
也许我们创建了一个新的函数，叫做，read-until。
Which is very useful in these kind of remote service challenges.
这在这些远程服务挑战中非常有用。
So read until shall fill up a buffer with single character reads, until the buffer contains
所以read until应该用单个字符的读来填充缓冲区，直到缓冲区包含
the magic string specified by read_until.
由read_-until指定的魔力字符串。
And then we can simply write, read_until the final1 prompt.
然后我们可以简单地写、读直到最后一个提示。
And then we can do our stuff.
然后我们可以做我们的事情。
So first we specify a username.
所以首先我们指定一个用户名。
Read until next prompt, then we specify the login password, and read again until next
读取到下一个提示，然后指定登录密码，然后再次读取直到下一个提示
prompt.
提示。
Another trick I use is the function raw_input(), which is actually to read input from the user
我使用的另一个技巧是函数raw_input() ，它实际上是从用户那里读取输入。
in python, but is very convenient to kinda pause the script, until we hit enter.
在python中，但是非常方便地暂停脚本，直到我们点击enter。
So when we execute this now, we connect to the service and then we wait until we hit
所以当我们现在执行这个时，我们连接到服务，然后等待直到
enter in the script.
在脚本中输入。
When we now check the running processes for final, we see two.
当我们现在检查运行过程的最终版本时，我们看到两个。
If you remember the one is the parent daemon, and the new one (with the higher process id)
如果您记得，其中一个是父守护进程，而新的守护进程（具有更高的进程ID）
is the spawned child that is handling our client connection.
是处理客户端连接的派生子级。
So we can attach gdb to that process and start collecting addresses of important symbols.
所以我们可以将gdb附加到这个过程中，并开始收集重要符号的地址。
So first let’s figure out the address of strncmp in the global offset table.
首先，让我们在全局偏移量表中计算strncmp的地址。
With info functions and a search term we can find the function trampoline in the plt quickly.
通过信息函数和搜索项，我们可以快速地在PLT中找到函数蹦床。
We can disassemble those instructions and we quickly see that it jumps to the address
我们可以把这些指令拆开，很快就能看到它跳到地址上。
stored here.
存放在这里。
And this points into the global offset table, and will obviously contain the real address
这指向全局偏移量表，显然包含实际地址
to strncmp in libc.
到libc中的strncmp。
So that is our target address we want to overwrite.
所以这是我们想要覆盖的目标地址。
Next is the address of system.
接下来是系统地址。
System is part of libc and we can quickly get the address of it here.
系统是libc的一部分，我们可以在这里快速获取它的地址。
Note, usually libc is randomized due to ASLR nowadays, but on this old linux system, or
注意，通常libc是由于aslr而随机化的，但是在这个旧的linux系统上，或者
on embedded devices, it still works this way.
在嵌入式设备上，它仍然以这种方式工作。
On a real modern system you would first have to leak addresses from memory in order to
在一个真正的现代系统中，为了
calculate offsets and break ASLR.
计算偏移量并断开aslr。
Ok, so we have our target and we have the address that we want to write to it.
好的，我们有我们的目标，我们有我们想写的地址。
Also the resulting log message will contain your source IP and port, which might vary
此外，生成的日志消息将包含源IP和端口，这可能会有所不同
in length.
在长度上。
Coming from localhost will be different than coming from a remote host.
来自本地主机将不同于来自远程主机。
So we should add this into our exploit to be reliable.
因此，我们应该将这一点加入到我们的开发中，以使其可靠。
The challenge used getpeername to get the ip and port of it’s peer.
挑战使用getpeername获取其对等机的IP和端口。
So we can use the equivalent to get your own name.
所以我们可以用等价物来得到你自己的名字。
With getsockname().
使用getsockname() 。
Now we also know the source ip and port and can write code to adapt accordingly.
现在我们也知道了源IP和端口，可以编写相应的代码来适应。
Also, I’m sorry, the code is really awful to read this way.
另外，我很抱歉，用这种方式读代码真的很糟糕。
I don’t know why I never bothered to turn on syntax code highltighing.
我不知道为什么我从不费心打开语法代码高速转换。
So here we go.
我们走吧。
Better late than never.
迟到总比不迟到好。
Syntax on.
语法。
Let’s have a look again at the logged line from earlier.
让我们再看看前面记录的行。
These characters here at the end look suspiciously like ascii, and when we convert them we see
结尾处的这些字符看起来可疑地像ASCII，当我们转换它们时，我们会看到
that they spell “Login from… and so forth”.
它们拼写为“从……登录等等”。
Let’s do this again with some recognizable characters to find the username.
让我们用一些可识别的字符再做一次，以找到用户名。
And there it is.
就在那里。
So it took roughly 14 pops of the stack to reach the username with the AAAA.
所以用aaaa访问用户名大约需要14个pop。
You can see that the A’s don’t perfectly align, and they even might shift around because
你可以看到A不完全对齐，它们甚至可能会移动，因为
of the length of the IP and port.
IP和端口的长度。
Thus first step is to make this constant by adapting the amount of As such that afterwards
因此，第一步是通过调整
it will be a known aligned offset.
这将是一个已知的对齐偏移量。
So in this case the hostname was 15 characters long.
因此，在本例中，主机名的长度为15个字符。
And one more A would have filled up and alligned the memory.
再加一个A就可以填满并重新标记记忆了。
So let’s think about what the shortest and longest hostname could be.
那么让我们考虑一下最短和最长的主机名是什么。
Shortest would be 9, longest 21.
最短的是9，最长的是21。
Because we prefer multiples of four to be 32bit aligned, we decide to pad to 24 characters.
因为我们更喜欢4的倍数是32位对齐的，所以我们决定填充到24个字符。
Thus we take the length of the hostname, subtract it from 24, and then we know how many A’s
因此，我们取主机名的长度，从24减去它，然后我们知道有多少个A
we need.
我们需要。
Let’s try this again with some %x in the username.
让我们用用户名中的一些%x再试一次。
Oh and we must not forget the newline at the end of our test inputs.
哦，我们不能忘记在测试输入结束时的换行符。
Oh, doesn’t work?
哦，不工作吗？
What did we do wrong?
我们做错了什么？
Ahh… we forgot the username and login command.
啊…我们忘了用户名和登录命令。
Still doesn’t work…
仍然不起作用…
Oh, the line can only be 128 bytes long, but we send a lot more with 28 of these %x…
哦，行的长度只能是128字节，但是我们用这些%x中的28个发送更多…
See, so many small things that can go wrong and slow you down.
你看，这么多小的事情会让你走错路，让你减速。
Now we get the login failed.
现在登录失败。
And looking into the syslog and searching for the Bs, we see that… god dammit… we
查看系统日志并搜索BS，我们看到……上帝啊，该死的……我们
forgot to add the padding with the As.
忘记用as添加填充。
Ok, there we go... the Bs are now perfectly aligned.
好了，我们开始……BS现在完全对齐。
Awesome.
令人惊叹的。
Now it doesn’t matter what IP or port you have, it will always be exactly there.
现在，无论您拥有什么IP或端口，它都将一直在那里。
And we can count the words on the stack and get the offset 17.
我们可以数一数堆栈上的单词，得到偏移量17。
So now we can move on and use a single %x with the dollar notation to refer to the 17th
现在我们可以继续使用一个带有美元符号的%x来表示第17个
parameter, the 17th value on the stack.
参数，堆栈上的第17个值。
So for example we can now place the address of the global offset table entry for strncmp
例如，我们现在可以放置strncmp的全局偏移表条目的地址
here into the string, and then use %n to write to that address.
在这里输入字符串，然后使用%n写入该地址。
So now we only need to figure out how big of a padding we need to write the values we
所以现在我们只需要知道填充有多大，我们需要写下
want.
想要。
If that confuses you, rewatch the old format string stuff.
如果这让您感到困惑，请重新包装旧格式的字符串资料。
So before we run it now, add another raw_input so that the script doesn’t exit and then
所以在我们现在运行它之前，添加另一个原始输入，这样脚本就不会退出，然后
we run it, attach to it with gdb, and observe the GOT entry for strncmp, we see that after
我们运行它，用gdb连接它，观察strncmp的got条目，然后看到
the login attempt it got overwritten.
登录尝试被覆盖。
Our goal is the lower part of the system address, which is 0xffb0.
我们的目标是系统地址的较低部分，即0xffb0。
So now we can calculate the correct number of characters we need to print.
现在我们可以计算出需要打印的正确字符数。
And this is basically how the process now works.
这就是这个过程现在的工作原理。
We write with %n to the address, check the number, calculate how much is missing or how
我们用%n写信到地址，核对号码，计算丢失了多少或如何
much we are overshooting, correct the number of characters we print and repeat until we
太多了，我们超调，更正我们打印的字符数，重复直到我们
have constructed the full address for system.
已构建系统的完整地址。
That is super annoying, it’s fiddly and takes some time, but once you got it, it’s
这太烦人了，很烦人，需要一些时间，但一旦你得到了它，它
so cool.
太酷了。
So now I got the offsets right and the address is overwritten with the address of system.
所以现在我得到了正确的偏移量，地址被系统的地址覆盖。
Now we can add the telnetlib trick with interact to our program and theoretically, at this
现在我们可以将telnetlib技巧和interaction添加到我们的程序中，理论上来说
point all calls to strncm would call system instead.
将所有对strncm的调用都指向系统。
And if you look into the code and think about that, simply writing something on the prompt
如果您研究代码并考虑一下，只需在提示符上写一些东西
should result in command execution.
应导致命令执行。
So let’s try it.
所以我们试试看。
We get a prompt, and now we can type commands as if we were in a real shell.
我们得到了一个提示，现在我们可以像在真正的shell中一样键入命令。
Every loop the program reads our line, calls strncmp, which in reality calls system and
程序读取我们的线路，调用strncmp，实际上它调用系统和
executes our commands.
执行我们的命令。
And again, we can copy the exploit to our windows machine, change the ip address to
同样，我们可以将漏洞复制到我们的Windows计算机上，将IP地址更改为
the VM and then get a remote shell.
然后得到一个远程shell。
Awesome!
令人惊叹的！